# PATRICK MWILA

+260-972-338-617· patrickmwila.org@gmail.com · @ndinecoder

### **TECH ENTHUSIAST, RESEARCHER & TEACHER**

I am a technology enthusiast obsessed with automating my workflows. Currently, I work for and provide services to The Information and Communications Technology Association of Zambia (ICTAZ).

#### STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

Crafting Scripts
Software Design Patterns
Project Management

Systems Designs & Configuration AWS Solutions Architect Associate Business Intelligence LaTeX Microsoft Office 365 Tools Microsoft Dynamics

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### ICT Association of Zambia Management Trainee

February 2024 - Present

- Set up and configured the first Electronic Voting System used during the ICTAZ April 2024 AGM in Livingstone, with guidance from NAPSA Head of Innovations, Mr. Eltone Makaliki.
- Designed and implemented the first back-office web application (ICTAZ Registration GUI
  Debugger), fully automating the resolution of registration errors for members. This resulted in more
  members being registered daily, increasing turnover.
- Collaborated on the design of the Software Requirements and Specification Document for the ICTAZ Event Management System, playing a crucial role in designing the main UML diagrams to showcase the major functionalities to be developed.

# ICT Association of Zambia Intern

January 2024 - February 2024

- ntern
- Learned and implemented fundamental concepts of customer service, focusing on user-centered delivery.
- Automated error resolution processes during customer registration by writing custom SQL scripts, resulting in a reduced workload.
- Demonstrated Linux server troubleshooting expertise by joining the team during a server downtime.
   Collaborated with Zamtel's on-site server infrastructure team to install Ubuntu 18.04, update configurations, and set up the ICTAZ Membership System.

# Northmead Secondary School Student Teacher

- · Taught computer studies and mathematics.
- · Created schemes of work, records of work, and lesson plans.
- · Assessed student performance.
- · Managed school activities.

# The University Of Zambia (UNZA) Awarded Paid Student Portal Developer

July 2023 - October 2023

Awarded paid student portal developer. Worked closely with a masters student, who was tasked to investigate the feasibility of designing and implementing a national scholarly research portal. The portal was intended to aggregate research produced in Zambia from different repositories and make it available to users. The user interface was designed to provide different facets for searching and filtering data.

### **EDUCATION**

### The University of Zambia

Bachelor of Information and Communication Technologies in Education (B.ICTs.Ed), ICTs with Mathematics

#### **Mpongwe Boarding Secondary School**

Grade 12 Certificate

### **REFERENCES**

## Mwasile Kowa, Finance and Accounts Executive @ ICTAZ

Telephone: +26 097 7737283

Email: mwasile.kowa@ictaz.org.zm

### Eltone Makaliki, ICT and Project Management Professional @ NAPSA

Telephone: +26 096 6157164 Email: eltonemakaliki@gmail.com

Lighton Phiri, PhD
Lecturer @ UNZA - Department of Library &
Information Science

Telephone: +26 096 1352662 Email: lighton.phiri@unza.zm